ISHA PATEL

patelisha1992@gmail.com | (639)-253-2592

https://www.linkedin.com/in/isha-patel-38866990/

1317 Chinook Gate Green SW, Airdrie, Alberta, T4B5J1

SUMMARY

Extensive experience in developing web applications using PHP, .NET, Java. Skilled in designing front-end as well as backend applications for more than 6 years in Banking and Finance domain. Expert to manage multiple projects concurrently to meet the required guidelines. Excellent communication & Interpersonal skills in teamwork and collaboration with demonstrated ability to explain highly technical concepts to the 'non-technical' audience. Paying attention to detail extends me to understanding the requirements, refining user interface/experience, optimized performance to deliver polished and user friendly web applications. Experienced in Identifying and resolved complex issues with great problem solving skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, XML, JavaScript, AJAX, JSON, Apache, XAMPP, WAMP, Java, PHP, .NET
- JavaScript Libraries: Jquery, Node.js, Bootstrap, React JS,
- Databases :MySQL, Oracle
 9-11g(TOAD), SQL Server 2008, SQL
 Plus
- Framework: Junit, TestNG, Cucumber,
- Methodologies : Agile, Waterfall
- Bug Tracking: Jira, Bugzilla
- Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, Power point, Visio, Outlook, Teams etc

- Test Case Management tools: Testlink, TestRails
- Version Control Tools: Github, SVN
- Build Tools: ANT, Maven
- Continuous Integration Tool: Jenkins
- IDE & Tools : Notepad++,
 DreamViewer, Eclipse, Netbeans,
 Intellij, Putty, Toad, Selenium IDE,
 Visual Studio
- **Web Services:** Rest Assured, Postman (API Testing)

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Acknowledged as "Best Employee of the year (2016-17)" for fastest deploying and developing and support for applications in a Team
- Received an Award for "Best Event Organizer" for organizing Annual Functions and International Women's Day Celebration (2018-19)

PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

QA Analyst, TCS Canada, Toronto, Canada

2022 – 2023

TCS (Tata Consultancy Service) is providing IT services, consulting & business the solutions with many of the largest businesses for the past 50 years

- Developed comprehensive test strategies and test plans based on the project requirements
- Conducted reviews within team, business as well as with stakeholders, based on comments maintained versions of plan and drafted emails for the approval of test plan from the business
- Reviewed and analyzed technical documents and business requirements to ensure accurate test coverage
- Created detailed test cases that covers all aspects of software quality

ISHA PATEL

patelisha1992@gmail.com | (639) 253-2592

- Reviewed test cases and provided feedback on test cases created by other testers to ensure completeness and consistency
- Executed test cases and document test results and maintained in HPALM
- Reported defects and track their resolution from developer team through defect triage sessions
- Actively participated in defect triage sessions and Ongoing live project issues
- Collaborate with development team to troubleshoot and resolve issues effectively
- Work closely with project stake holders including developers, business analyst, other QA team members to ensure alignment of testing
- Participated in projects meetings and provided updates on testing progress and issues
- Manage daily/weekly progress status report and defect tracking and resolution progress
- Ensured the execution of smoke, functional and regressions tests in all levels of the environments
- Lead in SWIFT Payments Technology projects, preparation and execution of testing strategies for client project engagements including Unit, Functional, System Integration and User Acceptance test phases according to the defined QA Framework
- Manage other QA analysts onshore/offshore for daily QA tasks
- Escalates issues and risks to project leadership in accordance with best practices
- Developing testing solutions that meet needs of clients and customers requirements
- Support regression testing efforts to ensure new features and not impact existing functionality

Web Developer, The Kalupur Com. Co. Op. Bank Ltd., Ahmedabad, India

2015 – 2020

KCCB Bank is a commercial co-operative multi state scheduled bank is providing services related to banking and finance operations from 1970

Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop and maintain web applications using Java, and other technologies. Designed and developed RESTful APIs for integration with third-party systems. Improved application security by implementing best practices and performing regular security audits.

- Developed RESTful APIs for integrating with third-party systems, resulting in a 20% increase in data accuracy.
- Improved application security by implementing best practices, resulting in zero security incidents for 2 years.
- Developed automated testing framework, resulting in a 40% reduction in testing time.
- Troubleshoot issues raised by end users and tracked in monitoring tool
- Expert in Relational Database such as Oracle, My SQL, SQL Server 2008
- Performed SQL Queries, procedures and functions in database tools like Toad, Oracle

Projects: Bank Website, Online Banking System (Internet Banking), Other In-house developed Application, Loan Processing System, Online Examination Tool, Online Documents Maintenance System

Web Designer Intern, Axis Techno lab Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

2014 - 2015

- Designed android mobile applications and website designs in PHP, .NET
- Performed database connectivity check, Connections between applications and database
- Designed images and banner using Photoshop tool
- Prepared documents like Technical Design Documents, User manual, Data dictionary record maintenance etc.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Full Stack Developer
Quality Assurance Analyst (Automation/Manual)

Certified for IT Security Examination, Indian Institute of Banking and Finance

2017

ISHA PATEL

<u>patelisha1992@gmail.com</u> | (639) 253-2592

Masters of Science - Information Technology (MSC-IT), Ganpat University, India	2012 – 2014
Bachelor in Computer Applications - (BCA), Ahmedabad University, India	2009 – 2012
Oracle Development Workshop, Ahmedabad University	2012